CHIMBUCHI EZEMADU

CUSTOMER SUPPORT SPECIALIST

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly skilled Customer Support Specialist with seven years of experience providing excellent aid to users from different industries, and collecting useful skills related to connecting with people, setting objectives, and handling projects. A history of rapidly understanding and adapting to new and complicated circumstances. Looking forward to exploiting a wide selection of assets in a stimulating and professional setting. Dedicated to learning and self-improvement.

WORK Experience

Customer Support Agent

Crossover for Work / Jun 2020 - May 2021

- Provided exceptional customer service with a Customer Satisfaction rate surpassing 90% for a variety of products such as Kayako, SchoolLoop, BiznessApps, ACRM, GoMembers, and OnDemand.
- Led frontline services with an emphasis on resolution, efficiency, emotional intelligence, and customer satisfaction for users on different platforms.
- Built strong customer relationships while handling delicate issues and rectifying complex issues.
- Identified, assessed, and offered solutions to intricate problems by utilizing knowledge bases of current issues, debugging tools, and lab simulations to create solutions that heightened productivity and effectiveness.
- Successfully held a First Contact Resolution rating of more than 80% and a CSAT score of higher than 90%.

Independent Project Contractor

APPEN Jan 2019 till date

- Examined and coordinated social media feedback and assessments for the Project Stop Fake News campaign of a well-known Tech company.
- Surveyed and classified social media material by utilizing a web-based tool to back up the collection of data.
- Appraised, arranged, and identified internet material based on explicit criteria.

ICT Support Specialist

Louisville Girls High School, Ogun / Jan 2016 – Jul 2018

- Organized the comprehensive renovation of the school's entire network system and established the audio-visual laboratory and electronic library.
- Conceived, created, and executed a school-wide WAN Infrastructure that
 enabled over seventy teachers and housemothers to submit/revise
 student scores, information, and class reports into the e-reporting
 application from their offices.
- Led the team that formed, implemented, and generated student e-reports for tests, successfully diminishing errors in e-reporting by over 80%.
- Formulated, built, and launched a secure WAN Infrastructure system for the school's accounts office to operate the school's accounting application in real-time.
- Decreased company costs by 45% through assertive vendor management and implemented cost-saving solutions, particularly printer paper/toner and bandwidth use, alongside advising the school management team on ICT matters.

<u>gbenga.ezemadu@outlook.com</u>

44 - 74230738866

Flat 4 Lazer House, 8 Castle Lane, Bedford MK40 3FA

EDUCATION

THE BELLS UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, OTA, OGUN

B. Tech Computer Science (Jul 2010)

SKILLS

LAN/WAN

Asp.net, MS SQL

Network Systems

Customer Success and Service

Problem Solver

Team Management

C#, Python, VMWARE

Microsoft Office Suite

Critical Thinking Skills

Database Management

SwishMax (for animations)

Web Development using HTML, Joomla, and WordPress

Adept in the usage of CRM tools like Zendesk and Zendesk Macros, Kayako, and Help Scout

CERTIFICATIONS

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management [Jan 2015]

Microsoft Certified Professional - Microsoft [Feb 2006]

 Devised, developed, and kept an up-to-date training manual for the IT section to carry out.

ICT Officer

African Commission on Human & People's Rights (AU) Mar 2014 – Mar 2015

- Collaborated as a member of a two-person team that supervised the comprehensive upgrade of the office building's network structure, restoring access to the African Union email servers and AU-wide telecommunication with an improvement in communication and internet availability of over 90%.
- Devised, modeled, and applied an office-wide security system that provided internet load balancing features, curtailing unauthorized access to some websites during office hours, and protecting against hacks and unapproved access to internet services.
- Formulated, designed, and incorporated an ICT equipment and accessories catalog system for the entire office for accurate documentation and tracking of ICT equipment and accessories movement.
- Implemented AU standard security policies on all office laptops and PCs to avert unauthorized access to sensitive material.
- Organized, constructed, and applied a WAN file-sharing system for members of diverse sub-groups working on related projects.

Technology Analyst/Admin Officer

Development Associates International, Oyo / Feb 2012 - Mar 2014

- Configured and defined parameters for installation or testing of local area network (LAN), wide area network (WAN), hubs, routers, switches, controllers, multiplexers, or related networking equipment.
- Configured wide area network (WAN) or local area network (LAN) routers and security settings/access permissions for groups or individuals.
- Installed new hardware or software systems or components, ensuring integration with existing network systems. Made travel arrangements for executives.
- Prepared responses to correspondence containing routine inquiries.

Technology Analyst

Directorate Of Administration, Governor's Office, Edo / Nov 2010 - Sep 2011